

Profile-Page: https://iamgiel.github.io/resume/

Profile

Web Developer skilled at both front-end and back-end technologies; specializing in Javascript and NODE.js with experience building applications with Angular and React. Strong analytical skills and creative problem solving with exceptional team project experience. Proficient with HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap/Materialize frameworks, JavaScript, Angular, React and NODE.js, Express, MongoDB and MySQL.

Tech Stack

HTML/CSS | Sass | Flex | Bootstrap | Materialize | handlebars | React | Angular | Express | Node | MongoDB | MySQL | MVC | Git Version Control | Media Queries | UI/UX | JavaScript | JQuery | Typescript

Experience

FREELANCE DEVELOPER (FULL STACK) - 12/2016 - PRESENT

- 1. Designed REST APIs that allow effective application integration
- 2. Created and deployed MEAN and MERN Stack applications using cloud services such as heroku
- 3. Used Angular5 and created a book exchange application.
- 4. Used a React front-end framework for a web application that queries NYTimes API, and allow users to search for a specific title and dates.
- 5. Designed a Liri Bot that used Twitter, OMDB and Spotify APIs all in a single node application.
- 6. Explored NODE packages that helped create Login and local authentication strategies.
- 7. Created a hangman game one in pure vanilla javascript in the browser and one played in your terminal using node packages.
- 8. Created a Star-Wars RPG Game with JQuery (https://iamgiel.github.io/star-wars/)
- 9. Created and designed 'home-made' object relational mapper for querying database.
- 10. Set and designed databases and schema for project called `For-Hire`
- 11. Designed and worked on the front end development team on a project called `The Reading Exchange` using angular5 animations.
- 12. Worked with Databases and schemas for MySQL and MongoDB.
- 13. Developed and designed ORMs such as sequelize and mongoose (and own modifications).
- 14. Worked extensively on Version Control GIT and use of github services.
- 15. Used Sass to refactor css codes and work on DRY code across application.
- 16. Extensive use of Nodejs libraries such as Passport for authentication and Socket.io for chat capabilities in web applications.
- 17. Use of various front responsive design frameworks such as Bootstrap, Materializecss, Material-ui for REACT, Sass-Angular5, JasneyBootstrap, GSAP for animation.

UNC CHAPEL HILL, FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE, UCLA 9/2017 - 04/2018

- Agile mindset while constantly working on an MVP
- Created a game of hangman with javascript and query
- Created Command Line Application using NPM libraries (fs, express, inquirer)
- Google Maps API, OAuths
- Use of bootstrap, materialize-css, and other html responsive templating
- Handlebars with Node Express Application
- Backend routes, connecting to server,
- Design MVC, Own ORM
- Designed database for a group project using MySQL and Sequelize
- Used validations, sessions, user login, passwords,
- MEAN and MERN web applications and deployment to heroku.

TRILOGY, WEB PROGRAMMING, UCLA 9/2016 - 11/2016

- Use of git version control
- Application cloud deployment Heroku.
- Used Media-Queries and Dev-Tools to create responsive web application.
- Used Bootstrap as front end framework for templating html
- Mobile first design
- Used Sass as css framework
- Use vanilla javascript to create logic for hangman game.
- Used Jquery along side javascript to run web applications

DIRECTOR OF TRAINING AND EMPLOYEE DEVELOPMENT, METIS TPS LLC – 2010-2017

- Produce and train Gaming Specialist who works alongside casino dealers to oversee company funds and to preserve the integrity of casino table games.
- Responsible for developing and delivering instructor-led, on-the-job, or a combination of these types of training programs including check lists, job aids, and other materials.
- Collaborate with shift-managers and supervisors reviewing current trends, updates, rules and policies that affect duties of Gaming Specialists and asset protection strategies for METIS.
- Find opportunities for employee development and training necessary to advance, and/or successfully completion of the technical skills of the job.
- Conduct interviews, screen applicant skills through live one-on-one timed testing on speed and timely responsiveness to errors on mathematical calculations of wins and losses, game hand comparisons and payouts.

CHINESE DOMINOES, TILES TRAINER FOR PT-GAMING 2009-2010

- A `Gaming Specialist` is the master of all technical aspects of the table from payouts to game rules and is responsible for verifying the accuracy of all mathematical transactions that occur during live play.
- Supervised and worked with casino staff, gaming associates. Communicating conflict of interests and balancing customer service.
- Responsible for accurate comparisons and creation of an ancient Chinese game called Pai-Gow Tiles.
- Observe Asset protection protocols and preserve integrity of the game.

- Observe quick table live payouts and call errors committed by dealers and players.
- Track scammers, card counters, and train associates for PT GAMING.

ASSET PROTECTION ASSOCIATE, 2008-2009

- Oversee all the rules of the assigned card game including, but not limited to: the various forms of casino games.
- Handle a functional command of the table and game while maximizing PT Gaming's involvement in the total table action.
- Maintain table game integrity while providing exceptional customer service.
- Communicate timely responses to errors, good eye on catching mistakes and accuracy on payouts and card comparisons.

Education

- UNC Chapel Hill CERT IFIED Web Developer 2017
- UCLA Coding Bootcamp 2016
- California State University, BS Education 2009
- Cerritos College AA TRAC Deans List 2007
- CSUF, Classical Guitar Performance Scholar, 2002-2004

Certifications:

- UDEMY Advance Javascript Cert(2018)
- UNC Chapel Hill Full-Stack Developer Certificate of Completion 2017
- UCLA Basic Web Programming 2016
- Freecodecamp ongoing (since 2016)
- Informatics Web Design (2001)